Contact

Raleigh NC 27612 (984) 228-0354 (Mobile) toufikaminew@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/taoufika (LinkedIn) lbladma.github.io/My_Portfolio/aboutMe.html (Portfolio)

aboutMe.html (Portfolio) github.com/lbladma (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Cybersecurity
Network Security
Identity & Access Management
(IAM)

Languages

French (Native or Bilingual)
Python (Limited Working)
HTML (Professional Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)
CSS (Professional Working)
Arabic (Native or Bilingual)
Spanish (Elementary)
Javascript (Elementary)

Certifications

Giving Your Elevator Pitch

CompTIA A+ (220-1001) Cert Prep 6: Physical Networking

CompTIA CySA+ (CS0-002) Cert Prep: 1 Threat Management

Programming Foundations: Web Security

Build a Full-Stack JavaScript Application Using AWS Amplify

Taoufik A.

Full Stack Developer and CyberSecurity professional in training-Team player-Passionate about helping/problem solving. On a mission to make the world a safer better place thru technology and love. 10+ years in IT

Raleigh

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer and an aspiring CyberSecurity professional with a Computer Science BA degree, and 10+ years experience working in IT as a senior computer engineer, system admin by day, and web designer by night which helped me accumulate couple of years experience working as a freelancer web designer.

Currently transferring my extensive IT experiences, skills, and knowledge towards specializing in Cybersecurity thru pursuing Security+ Cert and completing the Cybersecurity Bootcamp at Springboard.

Throughout my 10+ years experience as an IT professional, I worked with 1000+ users/clients/vendors, and used multiple systems and technology tools to support them and make sure best security practices are in place.

This exposure to technology and user based support which directly involves security. I was able to accumulate enough skills and experience to say that I'm confident to take on any role and tasks that are related to security and technology in general That being said, I'm always eager to learn and gain more experience, skills, and tools to tackle the evolving and new technologies and stay up to date.

My passion for technology, helping others, and making the life of anyone who depends on technology easy and safe is what motivates me to be who I am now, do my best and excel at what I do.

Experience

Springboard

Cyber Security Career track Student-Network Security-IAM-CIA triad-Mobile Security-System Hardening November 2021 - Present (7 months)

remote

Springboard's Cyber Security Career track is A 380+ hour online cybersecurity course that covers threat modeling, host-based security, network security, identity and access management, application security, network scanning, packet capture analysis, and vulnerability assessment. Includes the use of tools such as Wireshark, Splunk, Kali

Linux, and Nmap. Mary Allen participated in weekly live 1:1 mentoring sessions with an industry experienced cybersecurity professional, and successfully completed a final capstone project,

"Penetration Assessment and Remediation Plan" that was reviewed by an independent industry expert.

Topics Covered:

Network scanning tools
Packet capture and log analysis
SIEM technology
IDS and IPS administration
Threat intelligence
Vulnerability assessments
Incident response
Digital Forensics
Kali Linux
IT Project Management
Host-Based Security
Network Security
Identity and Access Management
Security Assessment and Testing
Security Operations

Mini-Projects Completed

System Hardening
Desktop Virtualization
Small Lab Design
Zero-Trust Presentation
Technical Security Assessment
Software Test

Security Assessment

SOC Strategy Presentation

Computer Forensic Lab

Python for Cybersecurity

AWS PCI DSS

PowerShell

Social Engineering

The Software Development Lifecycle

Web Application Vulnerability Remediation

HCL America, Inc.

Senior Hardware and Software Analyst

January 2020 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Coordinate and manage relationships with vendors and support staff that provide hardware / software / network problem resolution.

Use the Incident Management System to document and manage problems and work requests and their respective resolutions and circumventions.

Respond to telephone calls, email, instant messages, and assigned tickets from users; Assign work orders / incidents to appropriate support teams and follow up until closure which helped 90% of backlog tickets, and meet 95% SLA metrics.

Participate in on-going training and departmental development which allowed the team to stay updated with policies and new procedures.

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Full Stack Developer May 2021 - November 2021 (7 months)

Raleigh-Durham-Chapel Hill Area

A 24-week coding boot camp with a fast-paced, immersive curriculum that covers a full-stack:

Computer Science applied to JavaScript

- -Algorithms (Searches, Sorts)
- -Efficiency
- -Time Complexity
- -Big O Notation
- -Data Structures

Browser Based Technologies

-HTML/CSS

- -JavaScript/jQuery
- -Responsive Design
- -Bootstrap
- -Handlebars
- -Local Storage, Session Storage, IndexedDB
- -React.js

Databases

- -MySQL
- -MongoDB

Server Side Development

- -User Authentication
- -Progressive Web Applications (PWAs)
- -MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)

API Interaction

- -API
- -JSON
- -AJAX

Tenet Healthcare

Taleo HealthStream Tier II Remote Support Specialist August 2019 - January 2020 (6 months)

Dallas, Texas, United States

Provided in person and phone support to internal employees in regards to Taleo software and other HR applications.

Worked with employees to troubleshoot, diagnose, and resolve system access and functionality issues.

Provided one-on-one system coaching/training as necessary.

Assisted the team in running reports and capturing metrics and complete 95% of related projects on time and as requested

Daily tasks included but not limited to answering calls. Responding to emails.

And reviewing tickets logs and handling requests in a timely manner.

Reported to team leads or manager with system issues outages and updates.

NEC Corporation

Level 2 Support Technician

October 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 3 months)

Provided technical assistance to corporate customers, vendors, service providers with the following: critical system failure, hardware or software issues, general questions, clarification on operational procedures, or require one-on-one training for specific functions with their personal computer. Developed or assisted in development of documentation and standard operating procedures and customer service guidelines relating to IT support of Retail Solutions support systems.

Worked with team members and management to ensure technical issues are handled and escalated.

Pei Wei

Tier III Restaurant Support Analyst March 2018 - April 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Supported in-house developed and third party applications such Aloha Mobile, NCR, Radiant, KDS QSR Auto, Command Center, CFC, MenuLink, Taleo, OLO, and multiple restaurant systems applications.

Used CCM,VNC,RDP to remote into restaurant File servers and terminals to troubleshoot any issues.

Scheduled and followed-up of service with vendors; provide hardware, network, and peripheral device installation and troubleshooting.

Brinker International Client Support Professional January 2017 - December 2017 (1 year)

Supported in-house developed and third applications such Aloha Mobile, NCR, Radiant, KDS QSR Auto, Command Center, CFC, MenuLink, Taleo, Used Windows Server 2003/2008 for AD related issues including but not limited to users/groups access rights/permission.

Worked with vendors to provide hardware, network, and peripheral device installation and troubleshooting.

D&H Distributing

Cloud Client Support Professional May 2016 - May 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Worked cohesively with regional teams and other groups to ensure client services and projects are deployed to plan.

Used PowerShell to perform multiple admin tasks, manage registry, and access event logs.

Used C3 cloud platform to access clients cloud portal. Troubleshoot any C3 log in or access issues.

Supported XenApp and used it to access clients' servers and virtual machines.

JWDanforth Onsite IT Technician January 2016 - May 2016 (5 months)

Buffalo, New York, United States

Deployed and managed multiple projects in place and ensured the completion by the due date and planned future projects.

Provided one on one, phone, and email support to troubleshoot users' technical problems, concerns and answer any technical questions

Configured and tested new assigned devices for users such as iPhones, iPads, Laptops, Surface Pros and worked the team to deploy all devices.

Used VMware/SCCM to remote into servers and VPCs to troubleshoot any issues.

Used Windows Server 2003/2008 for AD related issues including but not limited to users/groups access rights/permission.

Women & Children's Hospital of Buffalo Epic Software Support May 2015 - April 2016 (1 year) Buffalo, New York, United States

Answered calls and responded to users' emails in regards to EPIC or any health system application.

Provided technical support to the hospital's staff including but not limited to doctors and nurses.

Helped users upgrade to the latest version of EPIC software system.

Route any non-related EPIC questions or concerns to the correct department or group.

Conducted follow up calls to users to ensure resolution and software full functionality.

EarthLink Internet
Desktop Support Engineer
February 2012 - May 2015 (3 years 4 months)

Performed application installation and Win7 compatibility testing, task sequence troubleshooting.

Communicated with the Level 1 Service Desk resources to document solutions to address common problems.

Performed reimaging/upgrade desktops and laptops using Inline or PXE boot. Diagnosed and resolved technical hardware and software issues.

Accurately documented, tracked, and monitored problems to ensure a timely resolution.

Education

Springboard

Cybersecurity Mastery Track, Cybersecurity · (November 2021 - May 2022)

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Full Stack development · (June 2021 - November 2021)

Franklin University

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Information Technology Project Management · (2009 - 2013)

The Ohio State University

Associate's degree, Information Technology · (2007 - 2009)